The Grateful Dead created an American
tradition unlike [music] any other.
>> Even after the Dead's last show in 1995,
the band has blazed a cosmic trail of
music and folklore that spans across
generations. [music]
>> But this year marks a new beginning in
the Dead's long, strange trip.
>> Because without Phil Lesh or Bob Weir,
and with the drummers Billy Kreutzmann
and Mickey Hart laying low, it's the
[music] first summer when there is no
clear inheritor of the Grateful Dead's
mantle, no center of the Deadhead
universe.
>> [music]
>> So, where does the music and the
community go from here?
>> NPR Music went on a Dead tour this
summer, interviewing fans, artists, and
archivists to figure out how the
Grateful Dead got to this point
>> [music]
>> and try to piece together what comes
next.
>> During this year's Days Between, from
August 1st [music] through August 9th,
we're publishing a series of stories,
podcasts, and more about what keeps
drawing people to the Grateful [music]
Dead and how they plan to carry it
forward.
>> Hear from Graham Lesh,
>> David Lemieux,
>> Don Was,
>> Dennis McNally,
>> Betty Cantor Jackson,
>> Andy Cohen, [music]
>> Jim James,
>> Jeff Tweedy,
>> and Deadheads from around the country.
>> Dead after death, coming August 1st.